<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Pixels / Clarity / Changeability</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Pixels / Clarity / Changeability</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Old Programming Wisdom Beats Crowdsourced Advice</title>
      <link>/crowd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crowd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Programmers as a crowd, like any crowd, are dumb. People find safety in following popular opinions. They see it as something of high value — worth sacrificing trust in their own instincts.
This is why I like to look for advice by turning to individuals who achieved something worth admiring and
show signs of independent thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re so Bad at Judging Complexity, yet We Like to Predict</title>
      <link>/complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/complexity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Living in a bubble, the one that&amp;rsquo;s unavoidable, makes us misjudge what are
the most complex things we have to face.
We think that some technical (software/hardware) problems are
the most convoluted ones, but actually, everyday things like traffic or sales are way more complex.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Notes on How to Design a Resilient UI</title>
      <link>/resilient-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resilient-ui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most interesting things happen once your software is in real use.
That&amp;rsquo;s when you can really see what&amp;rsquo;s working and what to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It brings us to the problem of editing already working thing. In the wild.
It happens all the time. Don&amp;rsquo;t think you can predict the future.
You need to design your software with ease of modification in mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Ford on What Promoted His Cars The Most</title>
      <link>/ford-marketing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ford-marketing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oldie but goodie. Quotes form Henry Ford&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;My Life and Work&lt;/i&gt; on his experiences with advertising/marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;racing&#34;&gt;Racing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I designed a two-cylinder enclosed engine of a more compact type than I had before used,
fitted it into a skeleton chassis,
found that I could make speed, and arranged a race with Winton.
We met on the Grosse Point track at Detroit.
I beat him. That was my first race, and it brought advertising of the only kind that people cared to read.
The public thought nothing of a car unless it made speed—unless it beat other racing cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Lazy Load Overuse and What You Can Do Instead</title>
      <link>/alt-lazy-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alt-lazy-load/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lazy Load is a great idea, so it&amp;rsquo;s overused frequently.
Do you remember that situation when you scrolled down
quickly to get to the middle part and the picture wasn&amp;rsquo;t there yet?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Planck on New Ideas and Creative Work</title>
      <link>/planck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/planck/</guid>
      <description>Here are few famous quotes related to creative work, by Max Planck:
 A new scientific truth does not triumph by convincing its opponents and making them see the light, but rather because its opponents eventually die, and a new generation grows up that is familiar with it.
  Anybody who has been seriously engaged in scientific work of any kind realizes that over the entrance to the gates of the temple of science are written the words: Ye must have faith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning UI Design from Coins (on Contrast)</title>
      <link>/ui-coins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ui-coins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contrast is an essential concept when it comes to UI usability. It solves more problems than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take coins as an example.
When it comes to look: at first glance you see differences in size, color (types of metals) and visual patterns.
Feel in hand is also important. Some seem heavier than others. You can detect size by touch too.
Each of these features is useful in some situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Payment UIs Can be Used to Reduce Friction</title>
      <link>/payment-ui-friction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/payment-ui-friction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A page with a final “buy” button or a credit card data form
is a huge friction trigger.
It&amp;rsquo;s the moment when you, as a buyer, think again about expense
and transaction safety.
The fact that you&amp;rsquo;re about to say bye to some of your money triggers that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Typography: Better Readability and Look</title>
      <link>/vim-typography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/vim-typography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few tricks to improve your Vim editor&amp;rsquo;s readability and theming.
All examples are for editing &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.gvimrc&lt;/code&gt; files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research vs Making Decisions</title>
      <link>/research-decision/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-decision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More often than not, research is something that prevents you from making a decision.
You want to be sure, so you seek more.
But your brain is somehow full of doubts all the time, no matter what you know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Ford for Makers: Quotes on Design</title>
      <link>/henry-ford-for-makers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/henry-ford-for-makers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are short excerpts from Henry Ford&amp;rsquo;s “My Life and Work”. I picked
the ones that will be helpful especially to makers — designers, developers, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;simplicity&#34;&gt;Simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My effort is in the direction of simplicity.
&amp;hellip;
Because nearly everything that we make is much
more complex than it needs to be.
Our clothing, our food, our household furnishings—all could be
much simpler than they now are and at the same time be better looking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintainable UI: How to Improve Code Editing with SASS</title>
      <link>/maintainable-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/maintainable-ui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Changes are unavoidable. And you can’t predict the future.
You also can’t solve problems in theory only, without prototyping.
So make your life easier and build things that are easy to edit.
Here are some examples of SASS based solutions that you can use to make UI more maintainable and “themable”.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
